In the first video about Hybrid A*,
Hybrid A*に関する最初のビデオでは
the update equations that we used were somewhat
私たちが使用した更新した方程式はほとんどのXYフィールド構成空間において
generic to most X Y field configuration spaces.
一般的なものでした
In particular, we don't specify what Omega is.
特に、Omegaがなんであるかは特定しません
Omega is the heading rate of change.
オメガは、変化の進行率です
Now for some robots,
一部のロボットでは
it might be that we can specify any omega independently of its state.
そのステートの ω を独立して指定できる場合があります
But that would mean that the robot can turn around its Z axis without constraints.
しかし ロボットはその Z 軸を制約なしで回転できるという意味になります
For car though, this is not very realistic,
でも自動車には これはあまり現実的ではありません
and we should probably use the bicycle model.
自転車モデルを使用した方がいいでしょう
This gives us an equation for Omega like this.
これは このような ω の方程式ができます
Here, 'L' is the distance between the front and rear axle,
ここの L は前と後ろの間の距離
'δ' is the steering angle and ⱴ is the constant positive velocity.
δ は ステアリング角度で ⱴ は一定の正の速度です
Now, for our Hybrid A* algorithm,
では Hybrid A* アルゴリズムの場合
we need to decide which configuration can be reached from the current node considered,
オープンセットに追加するために どのコンフィギュレーションが現在考えているノードから
in order to add them to the open set.
到達可能か決定しなければなりません
In practice, we would probably use some number of
実際に 左のスチール最大角度と右のスチール最大角度の間から
steering angles between maximum left steer and maximum right steer angle.
ステアリング角度を使用してみます
But the more different Deltas you add the longer it takes for your algorithm to complete.
ただし 異なる Δ を追加すればするほど アルゴリズムが完了するのに時間がかかります
Therefore, in this example,
よって この例では
we will only choose three angles to pick delta from;
Δを選択するために 3 つの角度のみを選択します
the maximum left steering angle,
最大左操舵角 ゼロ操舵角
zero steering angle and the maximum right steering angle.
及び最大右操舵角です
In the case of a car that can turn its wheels 35 degrees at most,
自動車がタイヤを最大 35 度回転できる場合は
that would be -35, 0 and 35.
これらの角度は -35 0 35 になります
This allows us to expand the search tree with three new motion primitives;
直進 左に曲がる 右に曲がるの
go straight, steer left and steer right.
3 つの新しいモーションプリミティブのある検索ツリーを展開できるようになります
Let's see how that works in a robot maze.
ロボット迷路でどうなるか やってみましょう
Let's say we have a maze like this.
このような迷路があるとします
The red square is the goal and this is the start position.
赤い四角がゴールで これがスタート地点です
The first thing we would do is add this cell to open list.
最初に行うことは このセルをオープンリストに追加することです
I'll use gray to indicate that.
それをグレーで示します
And then we would generate three trajectories,
そして 3 つのトラジェクトリーを作成します
the one for going straight,
1 つは直進
the one for turning right,
次が右に曲がる
the one for turning left.
最後に左に曲がるです
And in this case, we can discard the trajectories that go off the map or collide.
この場合では 地図から出てしまったり 衝突するトラジェクトリーなどは考えません
This gives us one new cell to open, which we do,
これで新しいセルが 1 つ開け
and then we mark the first cell closed which am indicating with this check-mark.
チェックマークがついている最初のセルを閉じます
Now, there is only one open cell so I choose to expend that one next.
今は オープンセルは 1 つだけなので 次のセルも展開します
And again, I generate the three trajectories from this stage,
ここでもう一度このステージで 3 つのトラジェクトリーを作成します
one of them is infeasible,
その中の 1 つは実行不可能なので
so let's not keep looking at it.
それのことは忘れましょう
And this leaves us with two new cells to open.
そして これにより 2 つの新しいセルが開けます
I close the previous.
前のセルを閉じます
Now there are two choices of what cell to expand.
ここでは 展開するセルには 2 つの選択があります
Assuming i have some heuristic that values being closer to the goal,
ゴールに近くなるヒューリックの値があると想定して
I choose the cell on the right,
右側のセルを選んで
and then generate trajectories from this new state.
この新しいステートからトラジェクトリーを作成します
Note, how, in all these steps,
これらのすべてのステップで どのように
I'm keeping track of,
トラックを残しているか見てください
not just what cell I am in,
今どこのセルにいるかというだけではなく
but also where in that cell I am, including orientation.
方向も含めて自分がいたセルがどこかというのも残しています
In practice, we could also use a three state space that include heading.
実際に ヘッディングも含め 3 つの状態スペースを使用することもできます
If we don't do that, then we're likely to prematurely close cells.
それをしなかった場合 はやくにセルを閉じてしまうようです
I'm not doing it that way here,
ビジュアライズすることは難しいので
mostly because it's harder to visualize.
ここではそのようにはやっていません
Let's keep going. I have three new cells to open.
それでは続けていきましょう3 つの新しいセルが開いています
I have to close the previous cell,
前のセルを閉じなければなりません
find the best option in the set of open cells and repeat.
オープンセルのセットのベストオプションを見つけて繰り返します
Again leaving me with three new cells to add to the open list.
また オープンリストに追加する新しい 3 つのセルを残しています
Which means I can close
そのため 前のセルを閉じることができ
the the previous cells and things get a little more interesting here.
ここはちょっとおもしろくなってきました
My heuristic will probably suggest that I expand
ヒューリスティックは おそらく一番下の右のセルを開いて
the lower right cell and generate trajectories from there.
そこからトラジェクトリーを作成するよう提案します
But this time, all of them would collide with the wall.
でも今回は すべて壁にぶつかってしまいます
Therefore, I don't need to add any new cell to the open set.
よって オープンセットに新しいセルを追加する必要はありません
Now, since I did expand this cell I have to mark it closed,
このセルを展開したので 閉じてチェックマークを付けます
and then I can look at my remaining open cells.
そして 残りのオープンセルを見ていきます
So same as before,
前と同じように
I take a closest cell the goal,
一番ゴールに近いセルに行き
generate trajectories, that is,
トラジェクトリーを生成します でも全部ぶつかるので
that all of these collides and close that cell.
そのセルは閉じます
Of the remaining open cells,
残りのオープンセルの
this upper right one is closest or the one with the best heuristic.
この右上のが一番近いセルか 一番いいヒューリスティックのセルです
So I repeat the process,
ゴールにたどり着くまで
on and on, until I reach the goal.
ずっとプロセスを繰り返していきます
Now, let's look at what this trajectory
では 一部のクラスターを取り除いて
really looks like by getting rid of some of the clutter.
実際のこのトラジェクトリーを見ていきましょう
And what we're left with is a continuous path,
私たちが残しているのは連続的なパスであり
that might not be the smoothest solution to our planning problem.
プランニング問題に一番スムーズな解決法ではないかもしれません
Indeed we can easily find examples of environment,
本当に 結果パスが人間のドライバーが
where the resulting path doesn't look very good compared to
この状況で通るパスと比べてあまりよくない環境の例は
what human drivers would have done in this situation.
簡単に見つけれます
And that's not the only problem.
これだけが問題ではありません
Sometimes, everyday stuff fails to even find the solution when one actually exists.
実際にはソリューションがあるにもかかわらず だれもそれを見つけられないこともあります
For example, let's go back to the stage in
多と言えば アルゴリズムのステージに戻って
the algorithm and consider what would happen if the map were slightly changed.
地図が少し変わった場合にどうなるかを考えてみましょう
In this case, we would have made all the same decisions up until this point.
この場合には このポイントまでは すべて同じ決定を行うと思います
But now we have close this crucial cell.
でも ここから この重要なセルを閉じてしまいます
Clearly, there is a path to the goal that could be reached.
明らかに ゴールにたどり着くパスはあります
But in these circumstances,
でも これらの状況では
Hybrid A* will not find any.
Hybrid A* は見つけれません
We can reduce the likelihood of this problem by increasing the resolution of
グリッドの解像度を増やし 進むために 3 次元を検索スペースに追加して
our grid or adding a third dimension to the search space for the heading.
この問題が起こる可能性を減らすことができます
Indeed, this would allow us not to close this position in the map for all headings
本当にこれで すべての進行方向で この問題が発生することを回避できるだけでなく
but only for a specific range which may allow us to find the solution in this-
特定の範囲でこれのソリューションを見つけることもできます